Finding Aid for George Romney Papers 1920s-1973
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Governor's Papers
  - Chronological
    - 1967
      - Federal
        - Legislation
          - Food Stamp Act (Box 195)
          - Guns (Box 195)
          - Sleeping Bear Dunes (Box 195)
      - Legislation
        - Miscellaneous [A-Z] (Box 196)
        - Abortion (Box 196)
        - Accountant's qualification (S.B. 20) (Box 196)
        - Ballot position of candidates in primaries (S.B. 647) (Box 196)
        - Daylight Savings Time (Box 196)
        - Guns (Box 196)
        - Women Workers (Box 196)
        - License Plates (Box 196)
        - Medical Examiners (Box 196)
        - Education (Box 196)
        - Liquor on Sunday (Box 196)
        - Special Session October 1967
          - General (Box 196)
          - Open Housing Petitions (Box 196)
    - 1968
      - Boards and Commissions
        - Budget Department
          - Glenn S. Allen file (Box 197)
          - General (Box 197)
          - Building Division (Box 197)
        - Administration, Department of
          - State Administrative Board Meetings (folders for each bi-weekly meeting, January-August) (Box 197)
          - State Administrative Board Meetings (folders for each bi-weekly meeting, September-December) (Box 198)
          - George Washington file (Box 198)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 198)
          - Council for the Arts (Box 198)
          - Retirement Boards
            - Judges Retirement Board (Box 198)
            - Probate Judges Retirement Board (Box 198)
            - Public School Employees Retirement Board (Box 198)
            - State Employees Retirement Board (Box 198)
          - Veterans Trust Fund
            - Audit Report (Box 198)
            - General [A-Z] (Box 198)
        - Agriculture, Department of
          - B. Dale Ball file (Box 198)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 198)
          - Insecticides (Pesticides) (Box 198)
          - Milk (Box 198)
          - Fair Authority (Box 199)
          - Racing Commission (Box 199)
          - Soil Conservation Commission (Box 199)
        - Attorney General
          - Frank Kelley file (Box 199)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 199)
          - Opinions (Box 199)
        - Civil Rights, Department of
          - Burton I. Gordin file (Box 199)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 199)
          - Housing (Box 199)
          - Appropriations (Box 199)
        - Civil Service, Department of
          - Franklin De Wald file (Box 199)
          - Grievances (De Wald notebook) (Box 199)
          - General [A-R] (Box 199)
          - General [S-Z] (Box 200)
        - Commerce Department
          - Herbert De Jonge file (Box 200)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 200)
          - Upper Great Lakes Regional Economic Development Commission (Box 200)
          - Aeronautics Board
            - General (Box 200)
            - St. Basil's (Box 200)
          - Banking Commission (Box 200)
          - Cemetery Commission (Box 200)
          - Corporation and Securities Commission (Box 200)
          - Economic Expansion
            - Bernard N. Conboy file (Box 200)
            - General [A-Z] (Box 200)
            - World Trade Advisory Council (Box 200)
            - Copper Peak Ski Area (Box 200)
            - Community Planning (Zoning of Property) (Box 200)
          - Insurance Commission
            - David Dykhouse file (Box 200)
            - General [A-L] (Box 200)
            - General [M-Z] (Box 201)
          - Liquor Control Commission
            - S. Thayer file (Box 201)
            - General [A-Z] (Box 201)
          - Public Service Commission
            - Peter B. Spivak file (Box 201)
            - General [A-Z] (Box 201)
          - State Planning Commission (Box 201)
        - Conservation Department
          - Ralph A. MacMullen file (Box 201)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 201)
          - Alewife Die-off (Box 201)
          - Deer (Box 201)
          - Interstate Oil Compact Commission (Box 201)
          - Natural Beauty (Box 201)
          - Natural Resources (Box 201)
          - Mackinac Island Park Commission (Box 201)
          - Parks (Box 201)
          - Tourist Council (Box 202)
            - General [A-Z] (Box 202)
          - Water Resources Commission
            - Lorning Oeming file (Box 202)
            - General [A-Z] (Box 202)
        - Corrections, Department of
          - Gus Harrison file (Box 203)
          - Pardons and Paroles (general) (Box 203)
          - Inmates [A-Z] (Box 203)
        - Education, Department of
          - Ira Polley file (Box 203)
          - Meeting of February 27-28 (Box 203)
          - Meeting of June 7 (Box 203)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 203)
          - School for the Blind (Box 203)
          - School for the Deaf (Box 203)
          - Michigan Rehabilitation Institute (Box 203)
          - Colleges
            - Miscellanea [A-Z] (Box 203)
            - Community College District (Box 203)
            - Central Michigan University (Box 203)
            - Eastern Michigan University (Box 204)
            - Ferris State College (Box 204)
            - Grand Valley College (Box 204)
            - Michigan State University (Box 204)
            - Michigan Technological University (Box 204)
            - Northern Michigan University (Box 204)
            - Saginaw Valley State College (Box 204)
            - Spring Arbor College (Box 204)
            - University of Michigan (Box 204)
            - Wayne State University (Box 204)
            - Western Michigan University (Box 204)
          - Higher Education Assistance Authority
            - General [A-Z] (Box 204)
          - Library Board (Box 204)
          - Vocational Rehabilitation
            - General [A-Z] (Box 204)
        - Highway Department
          - Howard E. Hill file (Box 204)
          - General [A-G] (Box 204)
          - General [H-Z] (Box 205)
          - Trees (Box 205)
          - I-696
            - General [A-Z] (Box 205)
          - International Bridge Authority (Box 205)
          - Mackinac Bridge Authority (Box 205)
        - Labor, Department of
          - Thomas Roumell File (Box 205)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 205)
          - Carnival Amusement Board (Box 206)
          - Manpower Training (Box 206)
          - Michigan Employment Security Commission
            - Malcolm Lovell, Jr. file (Box 206)
            - Irregularities (Box 206)
            - General [A-Z] (Box 206)
          - Labor Mediation Board
            - General (Box 206)
            - Detroit Newspaper Strike
              - General [A-Z] (Box 206)
              - Correspondence; memos, and press releases (Box 206)
            - Lansing Firefighters, Local No. 421 (Box 206)
          - Workmen's Compensation Board (Box 207)
            - Weldon O. Yeager file (Box 207)
            - General [A-Z] (Box 207)
            - Appeal Board (Box 207)
        - Licensing and Regulation, Department of
          - Lenton Sculthorpe file (Box 207)
          - General (Box 207)
          - Accountancy board (Box 207)
          - Architects Board (Box 207)
          - Athletic Board of Control (Box 207)
          - Barber Board (Box 207)
          - Basic Science (Box 207)
          - Chiropractic Board (Box 207)
          - Corporation and Securities Commission (Box 207)
          - Cosmetology Board (Box 207)
          - Dentistry Board (Box 207)
          - Electrical Board (Box 207)
          - Horology (Box 207)
          - Law Board (Box 207)
          - Medicine Board (Box 207)
          - Mortuary Science (Box 207)
          - Nursing Board (Box 207)
          - Optometry Board (Box 207)
          - Pharmacy Board (Box 207)
          - Physical Therapy Division (Box 207)
          - Plumbing Board (Box 207)
          - Private Employment Board (Box 207)
          - Real Estate Board (Box 207)
        - Mental Health, Department of
          - William H. Anderson file (Box 207)
          - Audit Reports (Box 207)
          - General [A-L] (Box 207)
          - General [M-Z] (Box 208)
          - Mt. Pleasant State Home and Training School (Box 208)
        - Military Affairs, Department of
          - Major General Clarence E. Schnipke file (Box 208)
          - Adjutant General file (Box 208)
          - National Guard [A-Z] (Box 208)
          - Veterans [A-Z] (Box 208)
          - Veterans Bonus (Box 208)
          - Selective Service [A-Z] (Box 208)
        - Police, State
          - Col. Frederick E. Davis file (Box 208)
          - Accident Reports (Box 208)
          - General [A-L] (Box 208)
          - General [M-Z] (Box 209)
          - Motorcycles (Box 209)
          - Civil Defense
            - Office of Emergency Planning (Box 209)
            - General (Box 209)
          - Safety Commission
            - Gerald W. Shipman file (Box 209)
            - General [A-Z] (Box 209)
        - Public Health, Department of
          - R.G. Rice file (Box 209)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 209)
          - Air Pollution
            - General [A-Z] (Box 209)
          - Alcoholism Board (Box 209)
          - Animals (Box 209)
          - Fluoridation (Box 209)
          - Crippled Children's Commission (Box 209)
          - Veterans Facility (Box 209)
        - Social Services, Department of
          - H. Bernard Houston file (Box 210)
          - Services for the Blind (Box 210)
          - Boy's Training School (Box 210)
          - Indian Affairs (Box 210)
          - Medi-Care (Box 210)
          - Medi-Caid (Box 210)
          - Nursing Homes (Box 210)
          - General (Box 210)
          - General [A-Z] [sampled] (Box 210)
          - Aging Commission (Box 211)
        - State, Department of
          - James Hare file (Box 211)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 211)
          - Historical Commission (Box 211)
        - Supreme Court (Box 211)
        - Treasury Department
          - Allison Green file (Box 211)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 211)
          - Escheats Board (Box 211)
          - Municipal Finance (Box 211)
          - Revenue Division
            - General [A-Z] (Box 211)
          - Tax Commission
            - General [A-Z] (Box 211)
          - Tax Appeal Board (Box 211)
        - Urban Affairs Commission (Box 211)
      - General Subjects
        - Accomplishments (Box 212)
        - American Motors (Box 212)
        - Appointments (Box 212)
        - Articles for Publication (Box 212)
        - Atomic Energy (Box 212)
        - Boy Scouts (Box 212)
        - Boys Clubs of Metropolitan Detroit (Box 212)
        - Capital Punishment (Box 212)
        - Celebrations (Box 212)
        - Civil Disorders
          - Material File (Box 212)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 212)
        - Communism (Box 212)
        - Community Chest (Box 212)
        - Conferences (Box 212)
        - Con-Con (Box 212)
        - Consulates (Box 212)
        - Council of State Governments (Box 212)
        - Counties of Michigan (Box 212)
        - Countries (Box 212)
        - Courts (Box 212)
        - Detroit, City of
          - General (Box 213)
          - New Detroit Committee (Box 213)
        - Disaster Relief (Box 213)
        - Divorce (Box 213)
        - Education
          - Material (Box 213)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 213)
          - Parochaid - Robo Citizens Letters (Box 213)
        - Elections (Box 213)
        - Employment (Box 213)
        - Executive Mansion (Box 213)
        - Executive Office (Box 213)
        - Executive Orders (Box 213)
        - Friend of the Court (Box 213)
        - Gambling (Box 214)
        - Governor's Conference (Box 214)
        - Governor's Mansion (Box 214)
        - Greater Michigan Foundation (Michigan Week) (Box 214)
        - HOPE (Box 214)
        - Housing [A-Z] (Box 214)
        - Immigration (Box 214)
        - Interviews [A-Z] (Box 214)
        - Introductions (Box 214)
        - Invitations Outgoing (Box 214)
        - Judgeships (Box 214)
        - Labor (Box 214)
        - Legal Aid Society (Box 214)
        - Legal Problems [A-Z] [sampled] (Box 214)
        - Legislature, Members of (Box 214)
        - Letters to Department Heads (Box 214)
        - Local Government [A-Z] (Box 214)
        - Meetings (Box 214)
        - Messages of Governor [A-Z] (Box 215)
        - Messages of Greeting [A-Z] (Box 215)
        - Mexican-American Affairs (Box 215)
        - Migrant Labor (Box 215)
        - Music (Box 215)
        - National Anthem (Box 216)
        - Ordinances (Box 216)
        - People-to-People (Box 216)
        - Police (Local) (Box 216)
        - Political (Box 216)
        - Radio, Television (Box 216)
        - Recommendations (Box 216)
        - Red Cross (Box 216)
        - Removal of Sheriff Peter Buback (Box 216)
        - Removals (Box 216)
        - Reorganization (Box 216)
        - Republican General [A-Z] (Box 216)
        - Republican National Committee (Box 216)
        - Republican State Central Committee
          - Elly Peterson file (Box 216)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 216)
          - Involvement Project (Box 216)
        - Young Republicans (Box 216)
        - Resolutions [A-Z] (Box 216)
        - Roads (Box 217)
        - Safety (Box 217)
        - Savings Bonds (Box 217)
        - School Bus (Box 217)
        - Sponsor (Box 217)
        - Statements for Publication [A-Z] (Box 217)
        - States (Box 217)
        - Subscriptions (Box 217)
        - Taxation
          - General [A-Z] (Box 217)
          - Aged [A-Z] (Box 217)
          - Income Tax [A-Z] (Box 217)
          - Intangibles Tax (Box 217)
        - Transportation (Box 217)
        - Unions (Box 217)
        - United Nations (Box 217)
        - Urban Affairs (Box 217)
        - Vacancy (Box 217)
        - Vietnam (General) (Box 217)
        - Vietnam Trip 1967 (Box 217)
        - Young American Medals (Box 217)
        - Miscellaneous [A-M] (Box 417)
        - Miscellaneous[N-Z] (Box 418)
      - Federal
        - Miscellaneous (Box 217)
        - International Situation (Box 217)
        - Physical Fitness (Box 217)
        - Prayer in School (Box 217)
        - Vietnam (Box 217)
        - U.S. Congress (Box 217)
        - Cabinet
          - Agriculture (Box 217)
          - Air Force Secretary [A-F] (Box 217)
          - Air Force Secretary [G-Z] (Box 218)
          - Army Secretary [A-Z] (Box 218)
          - Attorney General (Box 218)
          - Commerce Department (Box 218)
          - Defense Department (Box 218)
          - Health, Education and Welfare, Department of
            - General (Box 218)
            - Social Security [A-Z] (Box 218)
          - Housing and Urban Development, Department of (Box 218)
          - Interior Department (Box 218)
          - Labor Department (Box 218)
          - Marines (Box 218)
          - Navy Secretary (Box 218)
          - Postmaster General (Box 218)
          - State, Secretary of (Box 218)
          - Transportation, Secretary of (Box 218)
          - Treasury, Secretary of (Box 218)
        - Executive Branch
          - Budget Bureau (Box 218)
          - Communications Commission (Box 218)
          - Intergovernmental Relations (Box 218)
          - Internal Revenue (Box 218)
          - International Joint Commission (Box 218)
          - International Situation (Box 218)
          - Interstate Commerce Commission (Box 218)
          - Power Commission (Box 218)
          - Small Business Commission (Box 218)
        - Legislation [A-Z] (Box 218)
      - Legislative Files
        - Miscellaneous [A-Z] (Box 219)
        - Abortion (Box 219)
        - Daylight Savings Time (Box 219)
        - Gun Control Law (correspondence and petitions) (Box 219)
        - Licensing of Nurses' Aides (Box 219)
        - Non-Public School Bill (Box 219)
        - Sunday Liquor Law (Box 219)
        - State of State Message
          - Positive responses (Box 219)
          - Negative responses (Box 219)
        - Press releases on legislation (Box 219)
  - Governor's Office
    The Governor's Office series consists of files created and maintained by individuals on Governor Romney's staff. The subseries include Topical File, 1962-1968, of Margaret Little, Press Office, Invitations, Governor Personal, Staff Files, and Study Commissions/Governor's Conferences, 1963-1968
    - Topical file of Margaret Little 1962-1968
      This is a file of personal papers maintained by Romney's secretary Margaret Little. The files have been arranged alphabetically by subject, and consist largely of correspondence, with some staff memoranda and assorted reports and published material. The provenance (or source) of this subseries has been partially clouded with its transfer to the library. It seems to be a file that Romney maintained before becoming governor and which he continued after he left office. It does not appear to be confidential in nature, although some of the correspondents did write on personal, as opposed to state, matters. Some staff materials have been improperly folded into this subseries, but it has not been possible to identify what belongs with the subseries and what has been added to it. For this reason, the Margaret Little files should be used in conjunction with related materials found within the Chronological Series, General Subject files and the Governor's Office Series, Staff Files.
      - 1962
        - Blacks, material about (Box 220)
        - Civil Rights (Box 220)
        - Civil Service, 2 folders (Box 220)
        - Constitutional Convention (Box 220)
        - Gambling Laws, etc. (Box 220)
        - General Motors (Box 220)
        - Lists (Box 220)
        - McKinney, Harold, Jr. (Box 220)
        - Magazines and Magazine Writers (Box 220)
        - Meharry Medical College (Box 220)
        - Newspapers and News Writers (Box 220)
        - Nomination Certificates (Box 220)
        - Publicity (Box 220)
        - Radio and TV (Box 220)
        - Republican Party (Box 220)
        - Research Committee (Box 220)
        - Right to Work (Box 220)
        - Romney, Lenore (correspondence) (Box 220)
        - Schools, Prayer in (Box 221)
        - Taxes and Taxation (Box 221)
      - 1963 (including some 1962)
        - Administrative Board (Box 221)
        - Aid to Dependent Children (Box 221)
        - American Motors Co. (Box 221)
        - Civil Defense (Box 221)
        - Civil Rights (Box 221)
        - Clergy (Box 221)
        - Conservation (Box 221)
        - Conservation Study Committee Report (Box 221)
        - Constitution (Box 221)
        - Corporation and Securities Commission (Box 221)
        - Detroit (Mayor Cavanagh) (Box 221)
        - Economic Development (Box 221)
        - Economic Expansion, 2 folders (Box 221)
        - Education (Box 221)
        - Elliot and State Central Committee (Box 221)
        - G.E.M. Panel, 2 folders (Box 222)
        - General Motors Corp. (Box 222)
        - Governors, Correspondence with (Box 222)
        - Governors' Conference (National), 4 folders (Box 222)
        - Health, Education and Welfare (Box 222)
        - House and Representatives (Box 222)
        - Hospitals and Related (Box 222)
        - Inauguration (Box 222)
        - Insurance (Box 222)
        - Israel (Box 222)
        - Labor, 2 folders (Box 222)
        - Legislative Matters (Box 222)
        - Lists (Christmas) (Box 222)
        - Mackinac Bridge (Box 222)
        - Mackinc Island (Box 222)
        - Martin, John B., Jr. (Box 222)
        - Mental Health and Mental Retardation (Box 222)
        - Michigan Employment Security Commission (Box 222)
        - Midwestern Governors' Conference (Box 222)
        - National (Box 222)
        - Newspapers and Newspaper Writers (Box 222)
        - Olympics (Box 222)
        - Personal (Miscellaneous) (Box 222)
        - Political (Miscellaneous) (Box 222)
        - Public Service Commission (Box 222)
        - Radio and TV (Box 222)
        - Reorganization, 2 folders (Box 222)
        - Republican Party (Box 222)
        - Republican Governors' Conference (Box 222)
        - Republican National Committee (Box 222)
        - State Department (Box 223)
        - Task Force (Box 223)
        - Taxes and Taxation, 4 folders (Box 223)
        - Traffic Safety (Box 223)
        - U.S. Congressmen (Box 223)
        - U.S. Government (Box 223)
        - University and Colleges (Box 223)
        - Volunteers (Romney) (Box 223)
        - Welfare and Related (Box 223)
        - General alphabetical file (by correspondent) 1964-1965 (Box 223)
      - 1964
        - Ad Boards (Box 224)
        - Apportionment, 2 folders (Box 224)
        - Attorney General, 3 folders (Box 224)
        - Auditor General (Box 224)
        - Budget, 5 folders (Box 224)
        - Colleges and University Matters (Box 224)
        - Controller (Box 224)
        - Detroit (Mayor Cavanagh) (Box 224)
        - Democratic Party (Box 224)
        - Economic Expansion (Box 224)
        - G.E.M. Panel (Box 224)
        - Governors' conference, 3 folders (Box 224)
        - Hate Literature (Box 224)
        - Highway (Box 224)
        - Jewish Organizations (Box 224)
        - Labor and Unions (Box 224)
        - Legislative Matters (Box 224)
        - Mackinac Bridge and Island (Box 225)
        - Manpower and Retraining (Box 225)
        - Midwestern Governors' Conference (Box 225)
        - Military (State and Federal) (Box 225)
        - Negro Matters (Box 225)
        - Newspapers and Columnists (Box 225)
        - Northern Great Lakes Area
          - Council speech, September 21 (Box 225)
        - Publicity, 2 folders (Box 225)
        - Representatives, House of (Box 225)
        - Republican Party, 6 folders (Box 225)
        - Republican Governors Association (Box 225)
        - Republican State Central Committee (Box 225)
        - Scranton, William (Box 225)
        - Senators (Box 225)
        - Seidman, William (Box 225)
        - Staff Meetings and Memoranda, 4 folders (Box 225)
        - Task Force (Box 225)
        - Taxes (Box 225)
        - U.S. Congress (Box 225)
        - Youth and Related (Box 225)
      - 1965
        - Allen, Glenn (Box 225)
        - Athletic Board of Control (Box 225)
        - Budget (Box 225)
        - Budget (Democrats) (Box 225)
        - Chrysler (Box 225)
        - Civil Service (Box 225)
        - Colleges and University (Box 226)
        - Controller, 2 folders (Box 226)
        - Copper County (T.B. Sanitorium) (Box 226)
        - Democratic Party Matters (Box 226)
        - Detroit and Mayor Cavanagh (Box 226)
        - G.E.M. Panel June 17, 1965 (Box 226)
        - Governors (other states), correspondence with (Box 226)
        - Highway Department (Box 226)
        - Johnson (President) and his Administration (Box 226)
        - Legislative Matters (Box 226)
        - List (Box 226)
        - McClaughry, John (Box 226)
        - Marriott, J. Willard 1964 (Box 226)
        - Mental Health Department (Box 226)
        - Midwestern Governors' Conference (Box 226)
        - Mott, C.S. (University of Michigan, Flint) (Box 226)
        - National (Box 226)
        - National Guard (Box 226)
        - Pending (Box 226)
        - Pornography and Obscene Literature (Box 226)
        - Reorganization (Box 226)
        - Republican Party (Box 226)
        - Romney Notes (Box 226)
        - Seidman (William) and Michigan Week Trip (Box 226)
        - Staff Memoranda (Box 226)
        - State of State Address (Box 226)
        - Task Force on Expenditure Management (Box 226)
        - Tax and Budget Material (Box 226)
        - U.S. Congress (Box 226)
        - Welfare and Related (Box 226)
      - 1966
        - Air Pollution (Box 227)
        - Budget (1966/67) (Box 227)
        - Elliott (Arthur) and Republican State Central Committee (Box 227)
        - G.E.M. Panel (Box 227)
        - Highway (Box 227)
        - Johnson (President) and his Administration (Box 227)